Samya Kansal

Counselling Psychologist

Dedicated psychologist with a strong mental health foundation, and expertise in CBT and SPSS, enhancing student well-being through individualized counseling and mental health programs.

Compassionate, multicultural, and committed to creating a supportive environment for adolescents, teenagers, and adults.

Work History

2024-07 - School Counselor

Current

Vibgyor High School, Gurugram
Enhanced student well-being through individual
counseling and informal assessments, facilitated mental
health awareness workshops on topics, collaborated on
ICPs, and engaged parents through educational
resources and seminars.

2023-02 - Psychology Intern

2023-04

Confidence Clinic, Gurugram

Conducted intake interviews and assessments,
maintained confidentiality, developed therapeutic
rapport, and created psychoeducational materials.

2022-10 - Clinical Psychology Intern

2022-10

Manthan Hospital Neuro-psychiatric Center, Gurugram Implemented evidence-based interventions, conducted assessments, and facilitated psychoeducational groups while supporting case management, psychiatric diagnosis, and conducting psychometric assessments.

2022-07 - Clinical Psychometrician Intern

2022-07

Saksham Child & Adolescent Clinic and SGRH, Janakpuri, And Karol Bagh

Trained in child and adolescent therapy, conducted assessments, integrated techniques for testing, and upheld ethical standards.

2021-04 - Psychologist Intern

2021-05

Moolchand Hospital, New Delhi Acquired hands-on experience in OPD, taking case histories, diagnoses, therapy, and psychological

Contact

Address

Gurgaon, IN 122001

Phone

7678120525

E-mail

samyakansal07@gmail.co

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/samyakansal-a9a1bb1b5

Skills

- Multicultural
 Competence
- Compassionate
- Group and individual therapy facilitator
- Counseling and therapy (CBT, DBT, Mindfulness, etc.)
- Special Education
- Crisis intervention strategies and solutionfocused
- Parent-teacher collaboration
- Empathetic and active listening
- Expertise in SPSS
- Individualized
 Education (IEP) and
 Counselling (ICP)
 programs
- Inter-personal Skills

evaluations while developing intervention strategies and enhancing client coping skills through stress management and mindfulness techniques.

Education

2022-07 - Master of Arts: Clinical Psychology

2024-05

Amity University - Noida

- Graduation with Distinction, 4, 2024
- 8.16 CGPA
- Recipient of Personal and Professional Skills Award, 2022-2024
- Elected as class representative, 2022-2024

2019-08 - Bachelor of Arts: Applied Psychology

2022-04

Amity University - Noida

- Hons., 6, 2022
- Graduation with Distinction, 6, 2022
- 8.02 CGPA

2018-04 - High School Diploma

2019-03

Apeejay School - Pitampura, Delhi

- Final Grade: 77 %
- Subjects: Physics, Chemistry, Biology, Home-Science, Physical Education

Certifications

Practitioner Certificate - Thematic Appreciation Test (TAT)

Accomplishments

- Published research paper: Relationship among Perceived Parenting Styles, Self-Concept, and Fear of Intimacy: A Correlational. Link to publication: https://ijip.in/articles/fear-of-intimacy/
- Dissertation: Relationship between spiritual intelligence, emotional intelligence, and personality among males and females: A co-relational research, (2022)
- Dissertation: The Influence of Perceived Parenting Styles and Self-Concept on Fear of Intimacy in Individuals, (2024)

Software

SPSS



MS Office

